# Alsharif Eid Nahas

## Front-end Developer

Energetic and passionate front-end developer with 4 years of experience who is devoted to creating simple and modern UX/UI designs and translating them to functional web applications. Specializes in using web application frameworks, such as Reactjs and Angularjs. In addition, skilled in building responsive web applications. Additionally worked in team environments following the agile methodology.

alsharifeid@gmail.com https://github.com/alsharifnahas alsharifeidnahas.com (347)241-4925

### **SKILLS**

Programming Languages

 ${\sf JavaScript} ({\sf ES6}), {\sf Vanilla\,JS}, {\sf J\,Query\,TypeScript}, {\sf HTML5}, {\sf CSS3}, {\sf C\#,C++}, {\sf Java}, {\sf Python}, {\sf PHP}, {\sf Sass}, {\sf LESS}, {\sf L$ 

Database Systems SQL Server, MySQL, Oracle, MongoDB, SQLite

Tools RESTful Api(s), MS Office, WordPress, Adobe Illustrator, VS Code, Website Deployment, Responsive Design,

Agile Development, UX/UI Design, JS Libraries

Frameworks React js, React Native, .Net, Bootstrap, Angular

Version Control Tools GitHub, Git

Language Proficiency

**PROJECTS** 

Arabic (Native), English (Fluent)

EPL Soccer Application

Angular

• Developed a soccer web application that fetches the league data from a RESTful api(livescore).

• The user is able to browse through the league's teams, fixtures, and view the league table.

Recipe Web Application

React JS

• Developed a recipe web application that fetches the recipes data from a RESTful api(Edamam).

• The user is able to search for the desired recipe, and viewing the recipe's list of ingredients.

Personal Website-Portfolio

React JS

• Developed and designed a responsive website that contains personal information and portfolio.

Radwa Company website

WordPress

• Developed a website for the company.

• The website provides all of the information about the company.

Android Developer Studio for Mobile Application

Bar-Pop 

• Mobile application that provides population matrices, event, and location data

to customers looking for nightlife venues through map interface.

Hospital Management System

JSP, MS SQL Server

• Worked with a team to develop a hospital management system.

• Developed the back-end of the application.

• Created the database and built the query string using a back-end language (Java).

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Freelance Web Developer

Self-Employed

Savannah, Georgia Current

• Developed and designed responsive websites for multiple of clients.

Helped other students, during college, with their personal websites.
Fixed technical issue related to the design and programming for multiple of websites.

Web Developer

Radwa Chicken Company

Savannah, Georgia 2018-Current

• Designed and developed the company's website using wordpress.

Updated the website whenever there was a new feature that needs to be added.

• Added and deleted the company's information on the website.

#### INVOLVEMENT

Dean's List

Treasurer of Association for Computing Machinery Member of the Association for Computing Machinery Member of the IEEE Georgia Southern University Georgia Southern University Georgia Southern University Savannah Tech College Savannah, Georgia Spring 2017 Savannah, Georgia 2017-2018 Savannah, Georgia 2016-2017

## **EDUCATION**

Georgia Southern University Bachelor of Science Computer Science

CS courses: Object-Oriented Programming, Networking, Database System,

Software Engineering, Data Structure, Operating System, Theory of Computation, and C++ Programming

Math courses: Applied Numerical Methods, Linear Algebra,

Probability & Statistics App

Savannah Tech College Associate Degree Computer Engineering Technology

Savannah, Georgia 2015-2019

Savannah, Georgia 2013-2014